

Alexey Sibirtsev

Berlin, Germany alexey.sibirtsev@gmail.com sibirtsev.github.io +49 1525 876 64 43 alexey.sibirtsev

COVER LETTER

Hello, My name is Alexey. I'm working as a software developer for more than 15 years. Mainly, I work with web development with technologies like PHP, MySQL (please see the full stack in the next part of CV). I'm really excited about codding C++. I'd learned C++ in university, and also took a couple of courses on Coursera, Udemy, and Pluralsight.

Yes. I'm not skilled in production C++ development, but I have big experience in different programming languages and the development of high load projects. I know why is important to use algorithms with low complexity, to save memory and the cost of memory allocation.

SKILLS

php	10+ years	html	10+ years	memcache[d]	redis
nginx	10+ years	javascript (not ES6)	10+ years	elasticsearch	aws
apache	6+ years	c/c++	0+ year	linux	jquery
mysql	10+ years	machine learning	1+ years	git	bash
mongodb	5+ years	sphinxsearch	9+ years	agile	scrum
python	1+ years	symfony (2, 3, 4)	2+ year	kanban	etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FLIXMOBILITY TECH GMBH, Senior Software Engineer

June 2020 - Now

Technologies:

- Microservice architecture, RESTful API
- PHP, MySQL, Symfony Framework, Docker, PHPUnit, Behat, Kafka, AWS

AUTO1 GROUP, Senior Software Engineer, Team Lead

May 2018 - May 2020

Responsibilities:

- Design and development of backend part of internal application
- Support current products of the company
- Manage cross-functional team

Technologies:

- Microservice architecture, RESTful API, GraphQL
- PHP 7, MySQL, Postgres, Symfony Framework, Docker, PHPUnit, Behat
- AWS: S3, EC2, ECS, SQS, SNS, Lambda

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

N1 TECH (NGS TECH, NGS), Head of Dev, Dev Lead, Data Scientist, Senior Developer Jul 2007 - Apr 2018

Projects:

- **realty.ngs.ru** property search site. Functions: project architecture development, programming, task management, team management
- **passport.ngs.ru** cross-domain authorization and access control service. Functions: project architecture development, programming, task management
- **n1.ru** property search site, new product. Functions: project architecture development, programming, task management, team management

Tasks:

- Image classification with convolution neural network the classifier of the images of announcements on 7 classes: the facade of a building, a room, a kitchen, a bathroom, an entrance, a view from a window, the scheme of an apartment, based on caffe framework
- Real estate price tracking system the system for collecting and analyzing property price data, based on php and mysql

EQUALITY SOLUTIONS, Lotus/Domino Developer

May 2006 - Jul 2007

Development and support of the company's products for foreign customers

EDUCATION

SPECIALIST (ALUMNUS). ELECTRONICS AND MICROELECTRONICS

2009

Novosibirsk State Technical University, Novosibirsk, Russia

SOCIAL LINKS

LinkedIn Facebook GitHub